illuminateed.com 2019-06-26

# Privacy Policy - Illuminate Education

## **Illuminate Education, Inc.**

Revised July 21, 2017

### **I. Your Privacy Rights Are Important To Us**

The privacy of students, their parents and guardians, and visitors of this website is important to Illuminate Education, Inc. (“Illuminate”). This Privacy Policy is intended to answer your questions about the privacy practices applicable to our Website, [www.illuminateed.com](https://www.illuminateed/.com), as well as the data Illuminate maintains on behalf of teachers, administrators, school districts, counties, and other educational institutions (“Educational Organizations”) throughout the country.

Illuminate partners with Educational Organizations to provide tools to collect, organize, and analyze data about the students and education professionals in their school, charter management organization, county and/or district. Educational Organizations collect information about students and their guardians, teachers, and other individuals which is then stored and processed by Illuminate. In these situations, the Educational Organization rather than Illuminate decides the reasons information will be collected and processed. Illuminate’s privacy and data security practices regarding such information are governed by the contract entered into between Illuminate and the Education Organization and applicable law. For details regarding the information your Educational Organization collects, the use of such information, and any permissible disclosures to third-parties, please contact your Educational Organization directly. This Privacy Policy does not cover the practices of companies that Illuminate does not own or control, or individuals who Illuminate does not manage.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please [Contact Us](mailto:help@illuminateED.com).

### **  II. Information We Collect Directly from You**

#### **Information Collected from Our Website**

Although you can visit our Website without telling us who you are, when you access our Website, our servers automatically gather information from your browser, such as your IP Address. Your IP address is a unique number assigned to your computer or device by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). Collecting IP addresses is a standard practice and is generally done automatically. Our servers may also track additional information, including but not limited to the pages of our Website that you visit or the services you use, the browser you are using, the operating system of your computer or mobile device, and the way you interact with our services. 

Illuminate may, from time to time, use a third-party service, such as Google Analytics, to collect and analyze this type of visitor data. We use this information for a number of purposes, including calculating usage levels, diagnosing server issues, improving our Website and services to better accommodate user patterns, and detecting and diminishing security threats.

#### **Cookies and Web Beacons**

We also use other automated collection tools, such as “cookies” and “web beacons”, to gather information from you and your computer while you are visiting our Website. A cookie is a small file stored on your computer that lets us know whether you’ve visited our Website or accessed our services before as well as your navigation experience during your visit. Our cookies do not contain or capture personal information. We use cookies to facilitate your access to our services, to enhance your experience, to increase security, and to recognize your computer or device. Cookies allow us to collect statistical information about the usage of our services and Website to improve functionality and design. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually adjust your browser’s settings to decline cookies or otherwise modify your browser’s interactions with cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, it is possible that some of our services’ features may not function properly.

On our public-facing webpages, including this one, we collect anonymous usage data to help us understand how visitors interact with our site.  If you contact us through a webform, we may link this information to you personally.

cookie

| 

use

| 

type

| 

privacy information

| 

persistence  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
_gat | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to throttle request rate. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 1 minute  
_ga | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to identify individual users anonymously. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 2 years  
_gid | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to identify individual users anonymously. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 24 hours  
visitor_id* | Used to identify individual users and their site navigation anonymously, unless you personally use a form on our site to contact us. | third-party | [Pardot Privacy Policy](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/) | 10 years  
s-9da4 | Used to understand geolocation, from which we can better customize the public pages.  Anonymous unless you personally use a form on our site to contact us. | third-party | [Terminus Privacy Policy](https://terminus.com/privacy-policy/) | 1 month  
d-a8e6 | Used to understand geolocation, from which we can better customize the public pages.  Anonymous unless you personally use a form on our site to contact us. | third-party | [Terminus Privacy Policy](https://terminus.com/privacy-policy/) | 1 month  
Facebook web beacon (pixel) | This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected in this way is anonymous to us, i.e. we do not see the personal data of individual users. However, these data are stored and processed by Facebook and if you have a Facebook account, they may use it to understand your activity. | third-party | [Facebook Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php) | One time  
  
#### **Credentialed Site**

Districts who utilize our software will have a dedicated web domain.  We do not store or share any information outside the scope necessary for the function of the application.  Cookie and third-party data sharing information is listed below.

#### **Cookies**

Illuminate Education uses cookies to collect anonymous usage data to help improve our product, plus encrypted session data which allows allow our application to know who you are and respond appropriately.

cookie

| 

use

| 

type

| 

privacy information

| 

persistence  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
_gat | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to throttle request rate. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 1 minute  
_ga | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to identify individual users anonymously. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 2 years  
_gid | Anonymous usage data for Google Analytics. Used to identify individual users anonymously. | third-party | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage) | 24 hours  
_pendo_* | Anonymous usage data for Pendo Analytics. Helps us understand what features and pages are used most, including user workflows. | third-party | [Pendo Privacy & Trust](https://www.pendo.io/support/trust/) | 100 days  
__cfduid | Set by the CloudFlare service to identify trusted web traffic and decrease load time. Does not correspond to any individual user. | third-party | [Illuminate Education's Privacy Policy](https://www.illuminateed.com/privacy-policy/) | 20 weeks  
atd_rl | Used to throttle request rates. | internal | [Illuminate Education's Privacy Policy](https://www.illuminateed.com/privacy-policy/) | Current session  
  
live_*

| Session cookie.  Keeps you logged in. | internal | [Illuminate Education's Privacy Policy](https://www.illuminateed.com/privacy-policy/) | Current session  
ied_auth_token | Allows users to be authorized to different portions of our application after log in. | internal | [Illuminate Education's Privacy Policy](https://www.illuminateed.com/privacy-policy/) | Current session  
* | Remaining cookies are utilized to assist with a delightful user experience.  For instance, these cookies may remember how you sort certain tables, the level of zoom you choose, or the current step you are on during the creation of an assessment. | internal | [Illuminate Education's Privacy Policy](https://www.illuminateed.com/privacy-policy/) | Current session  
  
#### **Third-Party Data Sharing**

The following third-party software helps us collect anonymous usage data to help improve our product.  Additional third-party software, including other applications that interact with Illuminate Education, are utilized when there is direct request from the customer.

third-party

| 

use

| 

privacy information  
  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics | We send Google Analytics anonymized data to help us understand what features and pages are used most, including user workflows. | [Google Analytics Cookie Usage](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage)  
Pendo | We send Pendo anonymized data to help us understand what features and pages are used most, including user workflows. | [Pendo Privacy & Trust](https://www.pendo.io/support/trust/)  
NewRelic | We send NewRelic anonymized data to help monitor server health. | [New Relic Data Security](https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/using-new-relic/new-relic-security/security/data-security)  
Pusher | We send anonymized event messages through Pusher for our Live Proctoring product. | [Pusher Data Protection](https://pusher.com/legal/data-protection)  
SwiftReach | We send text messages, voice calls and emails initiated by teachers and administrators via the SwiftReach texting service. | [SwiftReach Privacy Policy](https://swiftreach.com/privacy-policy/)  
_User-initiated_ | Additional third-party software, including other applications that interact with Illuminate Education, are utilized when there is direct request from the customer. |   
  
#### **Email Marketing**

Email marketing sent by Illuminate may contain web beacons and other similar technologies to track the response rate to such communications. Web beacons (also known as pixel gifs, pixel tags, clear gifs, third-party pixels, or targeting pixels) are small graphics with a unique piece of identifying code, similar to a cookie, used to track the online movements of a web user or to access previously set cookies. These tools are used in email communications to determine whether messages have been opened or otherwise acted upon.

#### **Do Not Track**

Our services and Website do not respond to your browser’s “do-not-track” signals or comparable mechanisms.

#### **Correspondence Received by Illuminate**

Individuals may correspond directly with Illuminate through our “Contact Us” link or through other supplied contact information. Any personal information submitted through such channels will be used only to respond to such communications. 

#### **Children under the Age of Thirteen**

Illuminate does not knowingly collect information about children under the age of thirteen through this marketing website. Student information for our credentialed district applications store and collect data as noted in section III below.

### **III. Information We Store On Behalf Of Educational Organizations**

Illuminate and the services it provides to Educational Organizations comply with applicable provisions of law, including the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”) and equivalent state laws.

#### **Student and Teacher Information**

Your Educational Organization uses Illuminate’s services to assist with the administration of school-related activities and to provide a streamlined way to collect, organize, access, and report your information for educational purposes. These uses are specific to each Educational Organization and are governed by the contract between Illuminate and your Educational Organization.

The data your Educational Organization stores on Illuminate’s systems may include the following information about students and their guardians:

  * Demographic information including name, mailing address, email address, and date of birth;
  * Student education records including your student’s grades, class enrollment, and behavioral records;
  * Health-related information including your student’s immunizations and vision and hearing screening results;
  * System usernames and passwords.

In addition to student/guardian information, Illuminate also stores data provided by Educational Organizations related to teachers and other school employees, such as:

  * Demographic information including the individual’s name, address, email address, and date of birth;
  * The individual’s ethnicity;
  * Credentials obtained and the granting institution;
  * Information about the individual’s employment with the Educational Organization;
  * System usernames and passwords.

Your Educational Institution determines the information collected, maintained, and processed using Illuminate’s services. If you have any questions regarding the collection, storage, and use of the information your Educational Institution shares with Illuminate, please contact your Educational Institution directly.

#### **Disclosure to Third Parties**

The disclosure of information stored on behalf of Educational Organizations is governed by the contract between Illuminate and each individual Educational Organization.  Except for the ways outlined in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose the information described in this section to any third party unless we believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with a court order or other legal process served on us or assist government enforcement agencies; (b) investigate or prevent suspected illegal activities or protect the security and integrity of Illuminate Education, Inc.; (c) enforce this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Service, or other binding agreements such as the contract between Illuminate and your Educational Organization; (d) take precautions against liability, investigate or defend against any third-party claims or allegations; or (e) exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Illuminate Education, Inc., its employees, customers, or others. 

Illuminate only shares information in the ways described in this Privacy Policy. We never sell student records or other user information to third parties. Illuminate stores such information in locations outside its facilities, such as on servers co-located with third-party hosting providers or with secure cloud-storage services. 

As we grow, we may buy or sell assets or business divisions. Generally, the information stored on our systems would be transferred in such a transaction. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of business combinations, including but not limited to mergers, divestitures, or dissolution. In the event of such a transaction, any successor entity that acquires your information will continue to be subject to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

#### **Review or Deletion of Records Maintained by Illuminate**

Parents, legal guardians, or students who have reached 18 years of age may review the student’s education records and correct erroneous information. To review or update your information to ensure its accuracy or to correct any errors and omissions, **please contact your Educational Organization directly**. 

Requests sent to Illuminate seeking a copy of such records, or demanding that Illuminate modify or delete any records that it maintains will be forwarded directly to the appropriate Educational Organization. Please note that even when records are modified or deleted from Illuminate’s active databases, copies may remain in data backups as necessary to comply with business or regulatory requirements.

### **IV. How We Protect Your Information**

Whether collected directly from our Website or maintained on behalf of your Educational Organization, protecting the privacy of your information is important to us. We take security measures—physical, electronic, and procedural—to help defend against the unauthorized access and disclosure of your information. In addition to the restrictions discussed in this Privacy Policy, our employees are required to comply with information security safeguards, and our systems are protected by technological measures to help prevent unauthorized individuals from gaining access.. The specific measures Illuminate takes to secure your information are defined by the contract between Illuminate and your Educational Organization. These measures meet or exceed the requirements of applicable federal and state law. Illuminate’s employees are trained to observe and comply with applicable federal and state privacy laws in the handling, processing, and storage of your information.

Despite these precautions, no system can be completely secure and there remains a risk that unauthorized access or use, hardware or software failure, human error, or a number of other factors may compromise the security of your information.

Information stored by Illuminate on behalf of Educational Organizations is retained for educational purposes, and ultimately disposed of, pursuant to the contract between Illuminate and the Educational Organization.

### **V. Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may update or modify this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in the way Illuminate maintains, uses, shares, or secures your information. Please check this policy each time you visit the Website or interact with our systems to ensure that you are aware of any revisions. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Policy to our Website. Your use of the Website or any Illuminate systems following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy and agree to be bound by its terms and conditions.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email, telephone, or postal mail:

**Email** :  [help@illuminateED.com](mailto:help@illuminateed.com)  
**Phone** :  949-242-0343  
**Address** :  
6531 Irvine Center Drive  
Suite 100  
Irvine, CA 92618
